[{"id": "595641df803c1f1ebcc4a02b", "question": "What is the ball, or flat plate, that sits on top of a flag pole called?", "answer": "Truck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b621", "question": "Who designed the Cambridge Z88 computer?", "answer": "Clive Sinclair", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac8", "question": "The folklore characters known as \"oni\" originated in which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a0", "question": "Which planet in our solar system is named after the Roman God of the sea?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a6b66c0f9723ab15cb56", "question": "Which US state banned alcohol from 1907 until 1966?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3bddc73aa70ea0b70ae9", "question": "Where is the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier located?", "answer": "Arlington National Cemetery, Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fa", "question": "Who wrote the 1991 novel \"The Deceiver\"?", "answer": "Frederick Forsyth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e4dcfe83fe1f2a824bb8", "question": "Anubis, the God of Death, had the head of a what?", "answer": "Jackal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5eb738c05e259d786908732f", "question": "Who was the first Roman Emperor?", "answer": "Augustus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133968e", "question": "Who received an Oscar for directing the 1986 movie \"Platoon\"?", "answer": "Oliver Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc0", "question": "David Bowie is known for his distinct voice type?", "answer": "Baritone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a810", "question": "Zagreb is the capital of what European country?", "answer": "Croatia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9b8b9364247bf200fb883", "question": "In the 1983 film \"National Lampoon's Vacation\", where were the Griswold's headed on their cross country trip?", "answer": "Walley World", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f6", "question": "What cut of steak got its name from the New York City coach stop where it was first served?", "answer": "Porterhouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ea", "question": "Who is the developer of the game series \"Gran Turismo\"?", "answer": "Polyphony Digital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c45b", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for gold?", "answer": "Au", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399c1", "question": "What comedy duo\u2019s movies include 1978\u2019s \"Up in Smoke\" and 1981\u2019s \"Nice  Dreams\"?", "answer": "Cheech and Chong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133908b", "question": "What TV series was based on the series of books by Laura Ingalls Wilder?", "answer": "Little House on the Prairie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff6", "question": "What is an eyrie?", "answer": "The nest of a bird of prey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d8", "question": "What is the eastern-most US state capital?", "answer": "Augusta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ec25668dc25ca9e12ef63e", "question": "What Ray Bradbury novel is named for temperature at which paper catches fire?", "answer": "Fahrenheit 451", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad4c", "question": "Who was the fifth president of the United States?", "answer": "James Monroe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ca", "question": "Who created the operating system \"Linux\"?", "answer": "Linus Torvalds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c6440775fa611bce67d0", "question": "Singapore's Marina Bay Sands hotel is home to the world's highest what?", "answer": "Swimming pool -- The hotel has on its rooftop an enormous infinity pool.  At 650 feet, it is the world's  highest swimming pool.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de3", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"muffin\"?", "answer": "German", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4a4349076251badbeab2", "question": "What holiday commemorates the day the last slaves were freed in Texas?", "answer": "Juneteenth -- It commemorates the day (June 19, 1865) that slaves in Galveston, Texas learned that they were free.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a51", "question": "In the novel \"Mrs. Mike\", the young Boston girl married a sergeant in what?", "answer": "The Royal Canadian Mounted Police", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff2114f31a458464a93c440", "question": "Emily Bronte\u2019s \"Wuthering Heights\" famously described which English naturescape?", "answer": "Yorkshire moorlands", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e38ceb0f6c8a670a7957c53", "question": "What actor has been killed by an Alien, a Predator, and a Terminator?", "answer": "Bill Paxton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e2d", "question": "Who is Ben Stiller's mother?", "answer": "Anne Meara", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394d0", "question": "What is the title of the bugle tune sounded as the introduction to a horse race?", "answer": "First Call", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02b", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", where did Stewie first meet his archenemy, Bertram?", "answer": "Inside Peter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd6", "question": "What TV show did \"Diagnosis Murder\" spin off from?", "answer": "Jake and the Fatman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7e", "question": "Baku is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Azerbaijan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b0e98e964118b2bb3809cc", "question": "On what day in February was the 2010 romantic comedy film \"Valentine\u2019s Day\" released?", "answer": "February 10", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a814", "question": "In what county is Chicago, Illinois located?", "answer": "Cook County", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad9e232e748bb36357acdf9", "question": "What year did Alfred Hitchcock release his first American made film?", "answer": "1940", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d00", "question": "In which movie did Angela Lansbury portray a witch?", "answer": "Bedknobs and Broomsticks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a58c", "question": "What interstate highway connects Boston and Seattle?", "answer": "I-90", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c8", "question": "What Notting Hill road is home to London's most famous antique market?", "answer": "Portobello Road", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0e", "question": "Moroni is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Comoros", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e981fe83fe1f2a824be8", "question": "What French entertainer, activist and secret agent had a pet cheetah named Chiquita?", "answer": "Josephine Baker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b443", "question": "Who was Joseph Merrick better known as?", "answer": "Elephant Man", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8588ec223966ae8f8806", "question": "What is the first \"Friday the 13th\" movie in which Jason dons his iconic mask?", "answer": "\"Friday the 13th Part III\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c502fbde8045e48466a5", "question": "What is chionophobia?", "answer": "Fear of snow.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b2", "question": "What is the name of the sword of King Arthur?", "answer": "Excalibur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339775", "question": "What movie contains the line, \"Sorry, we would have come earlier but your husband wasn't dead yet\"?", "answer": "Naked Gun", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67f", "question": "Who was the first American president to appear on the cover of \"People\" magazine?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3589615db0d66a186cb54a", "question": "Which popular artist was born as Robyn Fenty in 1988 in Barbados?", "answer": "Rihanna", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb23", "question": "What NFL team did the Denver Broncos defeat to win their second Super Bowl?", "answer": "Atlanta Falcons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cbf", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional \"The Water Buffaloes\" fraternity?", "answer": "The Flintstones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb15", "question": "What city was home to the NBA's Jazz before moving to Utah?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990af40b72eedf883a8c705", "question": "What is Chopin's \"Piano Sonata No. 2\" also known as?", "answer": "The Funeral March", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a9d720565ad31a57c80b", "question": "The \"Star-Spangled Banner\" was written during which war?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008f18cf842fa4c4ba96b8", "question": "What did William H. Seward buy from Russia in 1867?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a899d9d60d398dc9cf7a6ad", "question": "What US Secretary of State received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1973?", "answer": "Henry Kissinger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81c48d0de9af39e9d4682", "question": "Who was the first U.S. president to be photographed?", "answer": "John Quincy Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac98", "question": "Which Italian city did Christopher Columbus claim he was born in?", "answer": "Genoa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f507ff048f679a45aad0", "question": "Necrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Death and dead things", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ef", "question": "Which US state is home to Joshua Tree National Park?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb59b55dad637d903c8814", "question": "What is the modern name for Van Diemen\u2019s Land?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6007805bbd51d85e222ab644", "question": "What group rebelled against the limitations of Impressionism?", "answer": "The\u00a0Post-Impressionists\u00a0rebelled against the Impressionists' naturalistic depiction of light and color.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339699", "question": "Which movie gave us the line \"You talkin' to me?\"", "answer": "Taxi Driver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a0", "question": "Happy Days was a spin off from what US TV show?", "answer": "Love American Style", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee9", "question": "In \"Uncle Tom's Cabin\", Eliza's famous flight across the ice floes takes place on what frozen river?", "answer": "The Ohio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974d", "question": "What is Alecia Moore better known as?", "answer": "P!NK", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe699a420565ad31a57c749", "question": "What was the first probe to land on Venus?", "answer": "Venera 9", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace9", "question": "What Harvard dropout held 535 US patents upon his death in 1991, second only to Thomas Edison?", "answer": "Edwin Land", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e8b", "question": "What species are mingled to produce a Hippocamp?", "answer": "Horse and fish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c748", "question": "What fruit is sometimes called a \"cooking banana\"?", "answer": "Plantain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b399", "question": "Who was the first president of the American Red Cross?", "answer": "Clara Barton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c88", "question": "Athos, Porthos and Aramis were collectively known as whom?", "answer": "The Three Musketeers", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a8", "question": "In 1990 Jennifer Aniston appeared in what short-lived TV show adapted from a popular movie?", "answer": "Ferris Bueller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a2246c0f9723ab15cb3f", "question": "Why did humans almost go extinct in 70,000 B.C.?", "answer": "Volcanic eruption", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff25b4d31a458464a93c477", "question": "On 1 April 1996, American restaurant chain Taco Bell tricked outsiders into believing it had purchased which historical monument?", "answer": "The Liberty Bell and renamed it the \"Taco Liberty Bell\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f0", "question": "Virginia McMath became famous as which actress?", "answer": "Ginger Rogers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d983708b8581f80b092ae", "question": "What game won the Game of the Year award at The Game Awards 2017?", "answer": "The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928d", "question": "What title was the movie \"Evil Dead III\" released under?", "answer": "Army of Darkness", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e097fe83fe1f2a824b90", "question": "Who is pictured on the highest denomination U.S. currency ever printed?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson is on the $100,000 bill.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf07", "question": "What is campanologist the study of?", "answer": "Bells", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe6", "question": "The US Midwest experienced a severe drought known as the Dust Bowl, during what decade?", "answer": "1930s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fedd8e66ce05a3942286d76", "question": "What was the nationality of Chief Bromden in the film \"One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest\"?", "answer": "Native American", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ddc", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"dungarees\"?", "answer": "Hindi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be7e", "question": "In 2006, what quarterback became the last USFL veteran to play in an NFL game?", "answer": "Doug Flutie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbe7", "question": "What was described as \"the tear on the face of eternity\"?", "answer": "The Taj Mahal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5a0", "question": "What do the letters LG stand for in the name of the international electronics and chemical brand LG?", "answer": "Lucky-Goldstar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc81aec223966ae8f888e", "question": "What is the name of the spider that paralyzes Frodo in the film \"The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King\"?", "answer": "Shelob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391fb", "question": "Who played Vincent Vega in \"Pulp Fiction\"?", "answer": "John Travolta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c651", "question": "How many daily tides are there?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ec2b15043630d44e5be228d", "question": "Who started the vision for the long-established fashion for the Kentucky Derby races?", "answer": "Col. Meriwether Lewis Clark Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f6d", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Bo and Luke Duke?", "answer": "The General Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c9", "question": "Who voices Homer Simpson in the TV show \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Dan Castellaneta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a37b", "question": "What is the capital of South Korea?", "answer": "Seoul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe77055eec85e375820b2f8", "question": "Which mountain range separates Europe from Asia?", "answer": "The Ural Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133961b", "question": "Queen scored the 1981 song \"Under Pressure\" with the help of what British singer?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a973", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Bundestag?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339493", "question": "What does Phil do for a living in the movie \"Groundhog Day\"?", "answer": "He is a weatherman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad8", "question": "In \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", what did my true love send to me on the sixth day?", "answer": "Six geese-a-laying", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338abe", "question": "Which author and philosopher is known for his works The Plague, The Outsider and The Fall?", "answer": "Albert Camus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c73b", "question": "What psychiatrist developed the principal of \"synchronicity\"?", "answer": "Carl Jung", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a237", "question": "What band released an album entitled \"Business as Usual\"?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a607", "question": "In which country would you find the state of Tabasco?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba7", "question": "What museum, designed by Frank Lloyd Wright, was opened in 1959?", "answer": "Guggenheim Museum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c989", "question": "Macrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Long waits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b27201dd7bf43be5e79d", "question": "What does a \"cusp\" birthday imply about your zodiac?", "answer": "Born between two signs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd1e4ec223966ae8f88c1", "question": "While filming \"Guardians of the Galaxy\", what did director James Gunn give out as rewards to his actors and crew?", "answer": "Play-Doh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd664a5a5bfecdd737e0857", "question": "How many people survived the Titanic sinking?", "answer": "706", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a410", "question": "Which US state is sometimes referred to as the Beaver State?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5989ae8fcb8751d53e7d7616", "question": "What was the first commercially successful method of manufacturing artificial gemstones?", "answer": "The Verneuil Process (also known as flame fusion)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c62b8ab0ae4aacefc17eee2", "question": "Metallica released what song on the album \"Mission: Impossible 2\"?", "answer": "I Disappear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1c", "question": "In what Australian state would you find Parkes?", "answer": "New South Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594d05491a1c922dd1ac64a1", "question": "Which islands were the subject of a war between Argentina and United Kingdom in the 1980s?", "answer": "Falklands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e97b06d333868d34d756", "question": "During World War II, what was the purpose of \"Operation Detachment\"?", "answer": "Capture Iwo Jima", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b56801dd7bf43be5e7d0", "question": "What does \"dachshund\" mean?", "answer": "Badger dog", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b62f", "question": "In the Western Union's alphabet what is the letter \"C\" known as?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f9", "question": "In the 1986 movie \"Labyrinth\", what disguise does the King of the Goblins visits Sarah's house under?", "answer": "An owl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339036", "question": "For what occassion did George Frideric Handel compose the anthem \"Zadok the Priest\"?", "answer": "Coronation of King George II", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c44", "question": "Mort Goldman from the TV show \"Family Guy\", is based on a character from what comedy duo?", "answer": "The Jerky Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf6", "question": "Which British physician developed the first effective vaccine against smallpox?", "answer": "Edward Jenner", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c87b877e98cb977789e6", "question": "In which country can you find Piedra del Pe\u00f1ol (also called El Pe\u00f1on de Guatape)?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cdb68e347d002c297e4dc", "question": "What does the energiser bunny wear on his feet?", "answer": "Flip flops", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bb35b4f2627b8fe95581beb", "question": "In ABC's \"Once Upon a Time\" what character was played by Colin O' Donoghue?", "answer": "Captain Hook", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08d", "question": "Who hosted the 1997 Grammy Awards?", "answer": "Ellen Degeneres", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ef", "question": "How many US States end with the letter N?", "answer": "4", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecdb56ec223966ae8f88f3", "question": "In \"Die Hard,\" how does John McClane signal officer Powell that something is wrong at Nakatomi Plaza?", "answer": "Drops a dead body on his car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aadb", "question": "What is the capital of Croatia?\u00a0", "answer": "Zagreb\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6017375e44491cbd7c5a1789", "question": "Who designed and built the interior structure of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "The innovative designer and builder Gustave Eiffel and his structural engineer, Maurice Koechlin designed and built the statue.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d7a02596a59cbdfbd3b8", "question": "Martha Jane Canary was a sharpshooting frontierswoman better known as?", "answer": "Calamity Jane", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fbae3fc0738315b1fb74e1d", "question": "Who won Chelsea's Player of the Year in 2012 and 2013?", "answer": "Juan Mata", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c77ce4f24f0f7a362efd546", "question": "A-ha and Edward Grieg hail from what country ", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf2", "question": "What year did actor Heath Ledger die?", "answer": "2008", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b156", "question": "How old was Lady Diana when she married Prince Charles?", "answer": "20", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c52ffbde8045e48466a8", "question": "What characteristic is unique to cetacean creatures?", "answer": "A blowhole -- Cetaceans (whales, porpoises, and dolphins)  use the blowhole on top of their head to breath oxygen.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c649", "question": "Where do bumblebees normally build their nests?", "answer": "Underground", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede4ae6ce05a3942286de0", "question": "In which 2001 movie did Tim Roth play the character General Thade?", "answer": "\"Planet of the Apes\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5c0d5dad637d903c881d", "question": "What is Valentine's Day referred to as in Finland?", "answer": "\"Friend's Day\"", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133961c", "question": "Who is Joe Dirt searching for in the 2001 movie by the same name?", "answer": "His parents", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ef", "question": "Kat Dennings and Beth Behrs play the lead roles in what CBS TV show?", "answer": "Two Broke Girls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9bb30364247bf200fb8a1", "question": "Which decade did the Bee Gees release the album \"Trafalgar\"?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339861", "question": "In Disney's \"Snow White\", what kind of animal heart does the Huntsman give to the Queen in place of Snow White's?", "answer": "A Pig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afb", "question": "What rock musician got his stage name from the yellow and black jerseys he used to wear?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0b", "question": "Who won a Pulitzer Prize for his novel \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbbe", "question": "Listed alphabetically, what would be the first property on a Monopoly game board?", "answer": "Atlantic Ave.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b153", "question": "On Christmas Day 800 A.D., who was coronated as emperor of the Holy Roman Empire?", "answer": "Charlemagne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3de244f0f6af5b066641", "question": "Andorra is part of which continent?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59049c60cf93664eb10486a6", "question": "What is the fear of the number 13 known as?", "answer": "Triskaidekaphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133954b", "question": "Who starred as David in the TV show \"The Hogan Family\"?", "answer": "Jason Bateman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a73d", "question": "Hells Canyon is located in which two US states?", "answer": "Idaho and Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af24c23844f4236002b95b3", "question": "Which two countries would you find Andorra sandwiched between?", "answer": "Spain and France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd70", "question": "What was the answer to the trivia question in the very first \"Got Milk\" ad, in 1993?", "answer": "Aaron Burr", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f33", "question": "Whose paintings include \"At the Moulin de la Galette\" and \"At the Moulin Rouge\"?", "answer": "Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60121a8a63c99d48cd169b03", "question": "What is the longest English word with only one vowel?", "answer": "Strengths", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a706", "question": "Cape Canaveral is located in which US state?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff2566b31a458464a93c460", "question": "What is traditional bubble gum made of?", "answer": "Chicle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febaee37e83c707845b20f8", "question": "What year was the first black hole discovered?", "answer": "1971", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c74e", "question": "What plant is the most common cause of hay fever?", "answer": "Ragweed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b261", "question": "What legendary chief's death in December 1890, led directly to the famous massacre at Wounded Knee?", "answer": "Sitting Bull's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e8", "question": "What surname for John in \"The Importance of Being Earnest\" did Oscar Wilde take from the seaside town he vacationed at?", "answer": "Worthing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e427fe83fe1f2a824bae", "question": "The Battle of Kursk is best described as what type of battle?", "answer": "A tank battle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600b88521d8c1817608d53f1", "question": "Roquefort, Feta and Manchego are all cheeses made from the milk of which animal?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c234", "question": "What do Teal Pumpkins represent to Trick or Treaters?", "answer": "Non-Food Treats", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133999f", "question": "In \"Back to the Future\", when Marty goes back in time, what does his mother think his first name is?", "answer": "Calvin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76a09eec85e375820b2b8", "question": "True champagne can only come from grapes grown in the Champagne region of what country?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338941", "question": "What creatures in \"The Lord of the Rings\" are referred to as goblins in the book \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "Orcs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6018bd9cd96d05b23b28165e", "question": "Who was the only British Pope ever?", "answer": "Pope Adrian IV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c2a", "question": "What American author created the characters of Rip Van Winkle and Ichabod Crane?", "answer": "Washington Irving", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a732", "question": "What river flows along the western border of Illinois?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f47", "question": "Who created the character of Rupert Bear?", "answer": "Mary Tourtel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c659", "question": "Which ape's name means \"man of the forest\"?", "answer": "Orangutan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600241144be4723ccac2216f", "question": "Which classic artist was a preacher before he was a painter?", "answer": "Vincent Van Gogh -- He spent nearly a decade of his life in different fields, including as an language teacher and lay preacher.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592eb021f83302ff91e46499", "question": "Who was the first Beatles bass player?", "answer": "Stu Sutcliffe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597ddd3e77980686f722d17d", "question": "When was the first permanent photograph taken?", "answer": "1826", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfed09dc5ec6cd98a832c", "question": "What writer had more than 70 different pen names?", "answer": "Lauran Bosworth Paine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e3", "question": "What did Harry Stone wear under his judge's robes on the TV show \"Night Court\"?", "answer": "Blue jeans", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b541", "question": "What does Seoul, the South Korean capital mean in the Korean language?", "answer": "The Capital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e7fdfe83fe1f2a824bd8", "question": "Who was the wife of the future Henry VIII\u2019s older brother, Arthur?", "answer": "Catherine of Aragon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c36c", "question": "What sign of the zodiac is the first air sign of the calender year?", "answer": "Aquarius", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6990a20565ad31a57c73f", "question": "What legendary athlete lit the Olympic torch at the 1996 Atlanta Olympics?", "answer": "Mohammed Ali", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab3e", "question": "Juba is the capital of which country?", "answer": "South Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339791", "question": "What KISS star sported the longest tongue in rock?", "answer": "Gene Simmons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9270574a5ce6b56b822d", "question": "What instrument in an automobile measures distance travelled?", "answer": "Odometer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7c3b62b316f4693fb67aa", "question": "Flour cooked together with fat is known as what?", "answer": "Roux", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59068132ff9c0647b50a8092", "question": "Who plays the role of Elliot Alderson in the TV show \"Mr. Robot\"?", "answer": "Rami Malek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e0", "question": "Where does SpongeBob SquarePants work?", "answer": "The Krusty Krab", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be8c", "question": "Who began his career as \"the Cherokee Kid\", the trick roper in Texas Jack's Wild West Circus?", "answer": "Will Rogers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff1", "question": "Under what name is Thomas Lanier Williams better known?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ee", "question": "Killer Whales are more commonly seen on which North American coast?", "answer": "West coast", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abfc", "question": "What English city was once known to the Romans as Venta Belgarum?", "answer": "Winchester", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc1", "question": "Where do fallen Norse warriors go?", "answer": "Valhalla", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3d18c73aa70ea0b70af3", "question": "What is the most mountainous country in the world?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac9", "question": "What chemical element is symbolized with Sn?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af04", "question": "What country did the U.S. declare war against in 1846?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad53", "question": "Who was the first woman to be entombed at the Pantheon on her own merit?", "answer": "Marie Curie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fb0", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Turn of the Screw\"?", "answer": "Henry James", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5907214c3745b36be73039f6", "question": "What is the name of the popular Christmas song that Will\u2019s dad composed in the 2002 film \"About a Boy\"?", "answer": "Santa\u2019s Super Sleigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338973", "question": "What century saw the death of Paul Cezanne?", "answer": "20th", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f164eaaf9b80650dbe7f936", "question": "What color is the \"Mind stone\" in the 2017 Marvel Legacy relaunch?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc4", "question": "Which part of India was occupied by the Japanese in World War II?", "answer": "The Andaman Islands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60137138138175489539638a", "question": "What nationality is Sir Anthony Hopkins?", "answer": "Welsh-American -- Born in Wales, he was naturalized an American citizen on April 12, 2000.\u00a0He maintains is British citizenship.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600240c94be4723ccac22168", "question": "In Tom Clancy's Jack Ryan novels, Jack graduates from what college?", "answer": "Boston College", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca91", "question": "What is a \"kiwano\" a type of?", "answer": "Fruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d0", "question": "By area, what is the smallest of the Great Lakes?", "answer": "Lake Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a537", "question": "The Catskill Mountains are part of what larger mountain chain?", "answer": "Appalachian Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c01c", "question": "What is James Naismith best known for?", "answer": "Inventing Basketball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b46", "question": "For which newspaper does Clark Kent work?", "answer": "The Daily Planet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f43d01dd7bf43be5e820", "question": "TBD stands for what?", "answer": "To Be Determined", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ea", "question": "What year did the band Human League initially release the album entitled \"Reproduction\"?", "answer": "1979", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf56", "question": "Which type of prepared bread is named after an opera singer?\u00a0", "answer": "Melba Toast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff66a0552a821ff76ae8b0a", "question": "A bell was removed from St.Patrick's tomb, 60 years after he died. What is this bell called?", "answer": "The Bell of Testament", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a8", "question": "What is singer Vanilla Ice's birth name?", "answer": "Robert Matthew Van Winkle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c780", "question": "Part of Dr. Eugene Shoemaker's ashes are buried at what unique place?", "answer": "The Moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b380", "question": "Which was the first suspension bridge over the River Thames in London?", "answer": "Hammersmith Bridge\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a93", "question": "What song appears on the \"Saturday Night Fever\" soundtrack twice, once by the Bee Gees and once by Tavares?", "answer": "More Than a Woman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb4697e83c707845b2119", "question": "\"Chicken of the Woods\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Mushroom", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3d4", "question": "Which waterfalls are between Lake Erie and Lake Ontario?", "answer": "Niagara Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa60", "question": "What two countries share Lake Geneva?", "answer": "France and Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b95", "question": "Who played the role of Basil Exposition in the three \"Austin Powers\" movies?", "answer": "Michael York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca3", "question": "What \"broke down\" according to the lyrics of the Looney Tunes theme song?", "answer": "The merry-go around", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a339", "question": "Heather O'Rourke was best known for her role in what movie franchise?", "answer": "Poltergeist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a898", "question": "What city is home to the Telstra Tower?", "answer": "Canberra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be6f", "question": "What is the Minute Maid Park also known as?", "answer": "The Juice Box", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b74a", "question": "What kind of patterns are Dutchman's puzzle, log cabin and Irish chain?", "answer": "Quilts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef61996ce05a3942286e54", "question": "Who was the first rock musician to famously smash their instrument on stage?", "answer": "Pete Townsend", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac8b", "question": "Who designed the famous collection of buildings in Oak Park, Illinois?", "answer": "Frank Lloyd Wright", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d070d1a1c922dd1ac64b4", "question": "Which town do Fred, Wilma, Barney, and Betty live in?", "answer": "Bedrock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7da1ff048f679a45abfa", "question": "Achluophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Darkness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133919a", "question": "What instrument does Jack White play in the band White Stripes?", "answer": "Guitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa564ec73aa70ea0b70b29", "question": "What type of dancing is usually performed in conjunction with May Day celebrations in England?", "answer": "Morris dance", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c8a84290aac110e416708d", "question": "Who said \"He that drinks his cider alone, let him catch his horse alone.\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59da1baef6756c9b30ba14fc", "question": "Kiev is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab149fbaab681b09292176", "question": "What year did GM first introduce the Corvette?", "answer": "1953", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0ec7469bb8041d07a064", "question": "Where is Labor Thanksgiving Day a national holiday on November 23rd every year?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b344", "question": "Which US President was known as \"the peanut president\"?", "answer": "Jimmy Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f05", "question": "What author created the character of Philip Marlowe?", "answer": "Raymond Chandler", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4eb", "question": "What does uranium become when it has lost all of its radioactivity?", "answer": "Lead", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a1", "question": "Who is known as Slim Shady?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392de", "question": "What new wave band recorded the 1978 album titled \"Parallel Lines\"?", "answer": "Blondie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76f", "question": "A \"brigantine\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Sailing ship", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d6", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Marble Man\"?", "answer": "Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339583", "question": "Who played the Captain of the fishing boat in the movie \"The Perfect Storm\"?", "answer": "George Clooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c997", "question": "What colour bill does a Greylag goose have?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e8a806d333868d34d74c", "question": "Where can you find Pont Du Gard, part of an ancient Roman aqueduct?", "answer": "N\u00eemes, France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015fbc6fe83fe1f2a824c3c", "question": "What's the name given to the unleavened bread that is consumed at Passover?", "answer": "Matzoh, which symbolizes the fact the Israelites were in such a hurry when they escaped, they did not have time for bread to rise.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b0a", "question": "What is the name of Sherlock Holmes' smarter brother?", "answer": "Mycroft", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef93446ce05a3942286e8c", "question": "Who was the first woman monster to appear in a movie?", "answer": "The Bride of Frankenstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c896", "question": "Where did the world's tallest bird, the giant moa, live until it went extinct around 1500?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5904a487cf93664eb10486c4", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", where did David and Katchoo first meet?", "answer": "In a museum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339624", "question": "Who starred as Danny Ocean in the 1960 movie \"Ocean's Eleven\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5db03f44aa1c9af2684d79a6", "question": "Who was the mother of the Minotaur?", "answer": "Pasipha\u00eb", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ba", "question": "What black stone is the most common volcanic rock on Earth?", "answer": "Basalt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59bb29d5c9bff04efae6d75a", "question": "Who wrote the novels \"The Joy Luck Club\" and \"The Kitchen God's Wife\"?", "answer": "Amy Tan's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133900d", "question": "What fruit was referred to as \"Golden Apple\" in Greek myth?", "answer": "Apricot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6e", "question": "Port Said lies on which waterway?", "answer": "The Suez Canal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393fc", "question": "\"Lord of the Dance\" star Michael Flatley was born in what country?", "answer": "The U.S.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b68f", "question": "Notch, peak, and shank are different types of what?", "answer": "Lapels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b0", "question": "Who played the role of Andy Dufresne in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Tim Robbins", "category": "entertainment"}]